LUIS SUAREZ

• Senior Software Engineer •

ABOUT ME

I have more than 8 years' experience working on software development projects.

I've worked with different methodologies such as SCRUM, Agile and RUP. Over those years he gains experiences working with SharePoint, C#, React, SQL, JavaScript, etc.

For me is important to feel as a team player and that can be seen in the way I lead my team, I like to help the team to generate a synergy to ensure they are delivering on the expected time with the best quality, but having in count we are working with human beings.

EDUCATION

Institucion universitaria de envigado, Envigado, Colombia Jan 2009 - Apr 2015 BS, Systems Engineering

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (native speaker)
- English (advanced)

SKILLS

- PowerApps development
- Azure DevOps
- CI/CD pipelines
- Power BI
- Logic Apps
- Azure infrastructure administration
- SharePoint Administration
- SharePoint Development (for 2007,2010,2 013,2016),
 - C# and JavaScript
- SharePoint Framework (for O365) SPFX
- Git repos
- NodeJS
- Mongo

- Serverless functions(Azure and AWS)
- GDPR compliance for O365 configurations
- React
- Angular
- Knockout
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- TypeScript
- C#
- SQL
- .NET
- .NET Core
- UX
- Project management
- Functional analysis
- Systems architecture
- Cosmos DB

LUIS SUAREZ

• Senior Software Engineer •

CAREER HISTORY

Perficient, Medellín (remote), Colombia Nov. 2021 - current Software Backend Specialist

- Assist our clients through the migration to O365 tenants (provisioning the tenant, Azure AD configuration, SharePoint and OneDrive Online configuration, BYOD.)
- Software backend specialist,

Capgemini, Medellin (remote), Colombia May. 2021 - Nov. 2021 Senior Software Engineer

- Start versioning PowerApps using CI pipelines to store versions of the solutions in Azure DevOps
- repos.
- Updating the client intranet from a high customized classic SharePoint to SPFX and power apps solutions, giving a better experience to the users and content administrators as well.

Globant, Medellin (remote), Colombia Jun. 2020 - May. 2021 SharePoint Developer architect

• Design and build a document management solution for client with by more than 10.000 end-users, using technologies such as O365, C#, SPFX with React

Disrupti-ca, Washington D.C. USA (remote) Jun. 2019 - Mar. 2020 Research and development Lead

- Creation of a remote conference tool that disrupt the market.
- Using common data services to automate information extraction from RFP and perform a ETL process
- to load the extracted data into a CRM.

Disrupti-ca, Washington D.C. USA (remote) 2018 - Mar. 2019 Dev consultant

• Development of a system which allowed to reduce the work time for action plans reviews around a 50%. Using .Net C#, React and Azure functions.

Grupo Argos, Medellin, Colombia 2018 - 2019

Product owner

- Lead several digital transformation projects.
- First Zero-paper project that includes digital signed documents for more than 5000 final users which
- allowed to reduce the work time from 5 weeks to 2 weeks.
- Develop inhouse solutions for internal systems evolve with the business needs using C#, MVC
- angular and React.

Integrupo, Sabaneta, Colombia 2017 - 2018

Senior developer

- First big project with SharePoint framework SPFX(React).
- Leading a small SharePoint dev team.
- Maintain and evolve enterprise custom software with an back-end built on API (C#) and Front-End in React

LUIS SUAREZ

• Senior Software Engineer •

CAREER HISTORY

Arkix, Medellin, Colombia 2016 - 2017 Senior developer

- First time managing a team (13 people) in a SharePoint migration project.
- Worked with C# MVC, API, web forms .net

EBFactory, Envigado, Colombia 2015 - 2016 Intermediate developer

- First contact with a multilateral.
- Fisrt formal experience with O365.
- Worked on the Agrimonitor website.
- Certified as SharePoint Developer.
- Worked projects in SQL, Socrata, C#, Angular and knockout.

Intergrupo, Medellin, Colombia 2013 - 2015 Junior Developer

- SharePoint 2007 farm migration to 2013.
- Very first migration of a .net custom application from framework 1.1 to 4.0
- Worked in projects using, C# API, entity framework, MVC, Angular.